Guide to the Stanford University, Board of Trustees, Records SC0282
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Board of Trustees, records
1884-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Board of Trustees
SC0282
17.75 Linear Feet
Records of the Trustees, 1897-2001, pertaining to legal issues, financial affairs, investments, academic departments, student housing, gifts received, real estate, campus development, and other administrative concerns. Also included are records pertaining to the Leland Stanford Junior Kindergarten Trust and its major beneficiary, the Golden Gate Kindergarten Association, 1884-1979.
Information about Access
The records are restricted until twenty years after the date of their creation.
Description of the Collection
Records of the Trustees, 1897-2000, pertaining to legal issues, financial affairs, investments, academic departments, student housing, gifts received, real estate, campus development, and other administrative concerns. Also included are records pertaining to the Leland Stanford Junior Kindergarten Trust and its major beneficiary, the Golden Gate Kindergarten Association, 1884-1979.
Biographical / Historical
Powers and Duties—The Board of Trustees is custodian of the endowment and all properties of the University. The Board administers the invested funds, sets the annual budget, and determines policies for the operation and control of the University. The powers and duties of the Board of Trustees derive from the Founding Grant, amendments, legislation, and court decrees. In addition, the Board operates under its own bylaws and a series of resolutions on major policy.
Membership—Board membership is set at 35, including the President of the University who serves ex officio and with vote. Trustees serve a five-year term and are eligible for appointment to one additional five-year term. At the conclusion of that term, a Trustee is not eligible for reelection until after a lapse of one year. Eight of the Trustees are elected or appointed in accordance with the Rules Governing the Election or Appointment of Alumni Nominated Trustees. They serve a five-year term.
Officers of the Board—The officers of the board are a chair, one or more vice chairs, a secretary, and an associate secretary. Officers are elected to one-year terms at the annual meeting in June, with the exception of the chair, who serves a two-year term. Their terms of office begin July 1.
Committees—Standing committees of the Board are Academic Policy, Planning, and Management; Alumni and External Affairs; Audit and Compliance; Development; Finance; Land and Buildings; the Medical Center; and Trusteeship. Special committees include Athletics, Compensation, Investment Responsibility, and Litigation.
Meetings—The Board generally meets five times each year.
Universities and colleges -- Administration.; Kindergarten.; Universities and colleges -- Finance.; College trustees.; Leland Stanford Junior Kindergarten Trust.; Golden Gate Kindergarten Association (San Francsico, Calif.); Stanford University. Board of Trustees; Stanford University. Board of Trustees
- Original Records, Series 1
  - Attorneys for Board (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lawsuits and claims (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Crank letters (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Publicity (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Investment analysis department (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Keys to office (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Office equipment and furnishings (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Supplies, requisitions for (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Petty cash fund San Francisco office (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Budget statements - monthly (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Post Office (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Files (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Taxation - University property (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Taxation - exemption from (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Stanford, Leland (Senator), estate of (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Form letters (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Invest policy - Stanford (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Merged fund (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Yield and gain pool (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Expendable funds pool (#10838) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Accounting methods and practice (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Accounting methods - institutional properties (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Worthless securities (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Special profits reserve fund (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Business manager, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Controller, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Financial Vice President’s office, 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Comptrollers office, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Assistant Business manager, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Instructions re. amortization, income, book value, etc., of securities, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Advices cash for investment (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Changes in merged portforlio, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bank accounts (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Wells Fargo Bank - commercial account (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Investment account - Wells Fargo (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Endowment savings account - Wells Fargo (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Wells Fargo Bank - agency account 2186 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Wells Fargo - current funds account #10838 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Standing instructions (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Safe deposit box (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Handling of securities - rules and regulations (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Security dealer accounts (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Mailing list for list of securities (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Insurance (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - President of University (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous data re. installation of Dr. Ray (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Graduate School of Business (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Bulletin (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Department of Law (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Libraries (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - School of Medicine (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cooper Medical College consolidation (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Music, department of (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Museum (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Chapel (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Mosaics (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hoover Library of War, Revolution and Peace (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Board of Athletic Control (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Stanford University Press (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Advertising solicited for University publications (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Pensions and retirements, staff benefits (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Carnegie Foundation for Advancement of Teaching (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Stanford Linear Accelerator (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Research Institute (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Palo Alto Hospital (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Land development (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Educational policies (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Traffic regulations - campus (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Student housing (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Student matters (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Religion (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Reports - general (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Annual reports - President (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Reports on trades complete, 13119 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Comparison of inventory (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Analysis of sales of securities (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous descriptive publications (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Inventory as of 12/1/35 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous comments by Committee prior to 12/31/35 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous comments by Paul Shoup (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Analysis of securities by others, 1941-1945 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Analysis of securities by others, 1936-1940 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - A - Gifts (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - (A-Z) American Relief Assoc. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - B (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - C - gifts (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - (A-Z) Commission for Relief in Belgium (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - (A-Z) George E. Crothers (Crothers Hall) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - (A-Z) George E. Crothers Law Scholarship (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - (A-Z) Ellwood P. and Helen Cubberley Fund (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - D (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dore, Estate of Charles H. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - E (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - E (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - (A-Z) Earl, Harley J. Earl (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - (A-Z) Estate of Frances C. Edwards (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - (A-Z) Harold and Winifred Ellott Funds - I, II, and III (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gifts - Elliott, John E. and John F. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - (A-Z) Elliott, John E. and John F. Memorial Fund (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - F (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - F - Gifts (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - G (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - G - Gifts (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - (A-Z) George E. Gamble Scholarship (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - (A-Z) 119 Grant Avenue (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - H - Gifts (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - (A-Z) William Webster Hansen Memorial Fund (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - (A-Z) Hewlett, Mr. and Mrs. W.R. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - (A-Z) Estate of Timothy Hopkins (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - (A-Z) Estate of Margaret D. Huston (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - I (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - I - Gifts (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - J (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - J - Gifts (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jacks, Margaret and Lee (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - K - Gifts (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - L (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - L - Gifts (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - M - Gifts (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Ma - Md (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Me - Mz (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - (A-Z) Floyd L. McElroy Investment Counsel Scholarship (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - (A-Z) Miller, James Irvin - Trust (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Gifts - Miller, James I. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - (A-Z) John Pearce Mitchell Fund (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - (A-Z) Lydia Pearce Mitchell (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - N (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - N - Gifts (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - O (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - O - Gifts (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - P (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - P - Gifts (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - (A-Z) Petroleum Investments Fund (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Q (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Q - Gifts (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - R (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - R - Gifts (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - (A-Z) Estate of Lotta P. Rossier (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - S - Gifts (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Sa - Sd (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Se - Ss (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - (A-Z) Estate of Solon Shedd (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - (A-Z) Shepard, Charles Hubert and Nellie B. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - (A-Z) Estate of Francis M. Shook (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - (A-Z) Stanley S. Simonson, Jr. Trust (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - St - St (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - (A-Z) Leland Stanford Jr. Memorial Scholarship (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Su - Sz (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - (A-Z) Estate of John M. Switzer (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - T (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - T - Gifts (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - (A-Z) Terman, Frederick Emmons (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - (A-Z) Donald B. and Mary C. Tresidder (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - U - V (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - U - V - Gifts (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - W (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - W - Gifts (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - (A-Z) Charles A. Wayland Fund (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - (A-Z) Weiss, Ephraim (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - (A-Z) Wilcox, Edwin A. and Mary S. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - (A-Z) Thomas and Dora Williams (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - (A-Z) Estate of Amelia E. S. Wilson (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - (A-Z) Woodbury, Alice estate of (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - X - Y - Z (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - X - Y -Z - Gifts (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Oil interests (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Real estate - general (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Real estate owned (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - (A-Z) Alameda lots (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - (A-Z) Berry Ranch (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - (A-Z) Carmel property (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - (A-Z) Federal Telegraph Building (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - (A-Z) Main and Folsom Street lot (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - (A-Z) Vina Ranch (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Real estate offerings - rejected (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - California - general (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Berkeley and Oakland (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - San Francisco (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Properties outside California (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Leases (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - (A-Z) Green, George. 604 Gilman, Palo Alto (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - (A-Z) Hale Bros. Store. San Jose (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - (A-Z) Hastings Clothing Company (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - (A-Z) Humble Oil. Tehama County (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - (A-Z) May, J. Earle. 601 Bryant, Palo Alto (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - (A-Z) Moore, Ltd. 1550 Broadway, Oakland (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - (A-Z) Palo Alto Hospital (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - (A-Z) Peninsula Pacific Construction Co. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - (A-Z) Gene Reid Drilling, Inc. (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - (A-Z) Stanford Convalescent Home (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Real estate loans (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Real estate loans policy - faculty and staff, etc. (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - (A-Z) John C. Almack (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - (A-Z) California Market Properties (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - (A-Z) Downtown Center Corporation (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - (A-Z) Howell D. Melvin (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - (A-Z) Pacific Union Club (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - (A-Z) University Club (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Loans - miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Spring Valley Water Company (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Felt Lake dam (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - San Francisquito Dam and Reservoir (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Gold Spike (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Carbon Hill Coal Company (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Bear Gulch Water Co. (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - A Contract for Maintaining a Taxicab Stand on the Stanford University Grounds, 1919-11 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    Scope and Contents
    Document sheds light on the business relations between the university and independent vendors operating on the premises. The agreement, signed by both the Business Manager of the Board of Trustees and one J. R. Andrus, allows the latter to operate a taxicab stand for one year, "opposite the book store and near the Stanford Union Building,"for the sum of one hundred and two dollars paid in gold. The contract also specifies that "the fare shall be twenty five cents for one passenger, fifty cents for two passengers,..." and so on and that the carrier (Andrus) "shall take special precautions to prevent damage to the roadway by the dripping of oil or gasoline..."
- Additional Records, Series 2
  - Advance Gift - Personal solicitation (AGPS), 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advance Gift - Personal solicitation (AGPS), East Bay, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Advance Gift - Personal solicitation (AGPS), San Francisco, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Advance Gift - Personal solicitation (AGPS), Marin County, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Advance Gift - Personal solicitation (AGPS), 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - CPA reports: work-study program, student union bonds, student housing bonds, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National Supply Co. of Delaware, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - National Supply Co. of Delaware, 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National Supply Co. of Delaware, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Leland Stanford Junior Kindergarten Trust: Internal Revenue Department (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Leland Stanford Junior Kindergarten Trust: tax matters other than annual forms (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Leland Stanford Junior Kindergarten Trust: Franchise Tax Board - California (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Leland Stanford Junior Kindergarten Trust: Minutes, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Leland Stanford Junior Kindergarten Trust: Period report of charitable trust - California (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Leland Stanford Junior Kindergarten Trust: material on Golden Gate Kindergarten Association (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Annual Reports, 1884-1910, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Leland Stanford Junior Kindergarten Trust accounts and correspondence: pages 1-10, 1907-1907 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bonds, list of (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence regarding book plates, 1909-1912 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1899-1920 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Earthquake, damage report, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Endowment, legal document, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Knoll, specifications for (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Legal documents, 1896-1907 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Leib, S., legal document and letter, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Medical School, H. Hoover to T. Hopkins, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Pebble Beach property, analysis, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Pulgas Rancho, map of Dr. Boring’s portion (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Roads, affadavits regarding closing, 1913-1914 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Stanford, Jane L., addresses to the Board, 1897-1902 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Trustee signatures (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Tuition, letter regarding instituion of fees, from student groups, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - University seal (examples) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Vina Ranch, reports on, 1915-1918 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Wilbur, Ray L., letter re future of University, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Committee Records, Series 3
  - Board of Trustees, Academic Affairs Committee, 1949-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees Academic Affairs Comittee, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees, Additional Matters, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees, Additional Matters, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees, Admission Plan Committtee, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Borad of Trustees, Annual Meetings, 1951-1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Borad of Trustees, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustees, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Building and Grounds Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1941-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Building and Grounds Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1941-1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Building and Grounds Committee, 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees Coordination Committee, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Finance Committee Minutes, 1918-1923 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Finance Committee Minutes, 1924-1928 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Finance Committee Minutes, 1928-1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Finance Committee Minutes, 1933-1936 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees Finance Committee, 1943-1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees Finance Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees Finance Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees Finance Committee, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees Investment Committee, 1945-1953 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees Investment Committee, 1949-1956 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees Investment Committee, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees, Land Development Committee, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees, Land Development Committee, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees, Land Development Committee, 1956-1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees, Committee on the Medical School, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustees, Committee on the Medical School, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees, Medical Sub-Committee, 1921-1924 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees, Planning and Development, 1945, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees, Planning and Development, 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees, Programs (Agendas) of Meetings, 1946-1954 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees Programs(Agendas) of Meetings, 1946-1954 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees, Special Meetings, 1950-1960 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - University Committee, 1918-1919 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - University Committee, 1919-1923 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - University Committee, 1923-1929 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - University Committee, 1929-1931 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - University Committee, 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - University Committee, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - University Committee, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - University Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - University Committee, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees-Finance Committee, 1907-1908 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees-Finance Commitee, 1906-1908 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees-Finance Commitee, 1906-1908 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees-Finance Commitee, 1907-1908 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees-Committee on Rules, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees, 1904-1908 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees, 1906-1908 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees, 1906-1907 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees, 1907-1908 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustees-Land and Building Development Committee, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees-Investment Responsibility Committee (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees- Committee on Investments, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees-Library Commitee, 1907-1908 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Board of Trustees-Special Committee on Cooper Medical College, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Board of Trustees-Special Committee on Cooper Medical College, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Board of Trustees, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2001-272
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Restricted 20 years from date of creation.
  - Bass Board miscellaneous, 1996- (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Faxes/Mailings, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Bass correspondence, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 6-14)
  - Board of Trustee correspondence (to and from Lowell, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 15-19)
  - Open Space Alliance, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Open Space Alliance, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Open Space Alliance, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Open Space Alliance, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Jasper Ridge, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Crangle, Mabry, Sawislak correspondence, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Golf Course letters, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Rose Bowl, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 2000 Feb (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Special Meeting [UCSF/Stanford Health Care], 1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Special Meeting [UCSF/Stanford Health Care], 1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Special Meeting [UCSF/Stanford Health Care], 1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Special Meeting [UCSF/Stanford Health Care], 1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Statement to Faculty Senate, 1999 Mar 4 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Casper, Gerhard. State of School [printed versions], 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - ADA Task Force (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - American Hellenic Institute, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Annual Review Panel, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Educational Leadership Program (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ginsberg / Leary Acquisitions (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - BOT notepads, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Harris, Justin [SU application], 1996 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Institute for International Studies, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
  - Managment Forum [missing], 1994 (Box 3)
  - Jefferson Lecture, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Korn/Ferry, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Lion Enterprises [underground storage tanks], 1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Madden v. Stanford tenure, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Marshall, Fred, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minority Alumni Caucus, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
  - Move information to 310, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Move information to 310, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Move information, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Multi-Cultural Advisory group, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - NRC - national research council survey, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dr. John Niederhuber (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - OMD Director Search, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Board Sec as Official Trader, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - University Fellows program, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Unversity Management Group, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Viswanathan, Usha, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - VP Planning & Management, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - COI Info (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - COI Compliance forms, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Conflict of Interest, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Conflict of Interest, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Trustee Handbook, 1998-99 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Revisions to Handbook, 1999-200 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Trustee Handbook, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Trustee Manual and Revisions (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
  - Trustee orientation Packets, 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Trustee orientation Packets, 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Trustee orientation Packets, 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Trustee orientation Packets, 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Trustee orientation Packets, 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Trustee orientation Packets, 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Trustee Reunion, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)